Skip to main content

Toggle navigation

TracFone Wireless, Inc. Privacy Policy
======================================

Effective Date: June 2024

Recent Changes: We review and update our Privacy Policy to reflect the changes that come with the development of new products, services, technologies and uses of information. In addition, we occasionally make organizational, stylistic and grammatical changes to make our policy easier to read. Below you’ll find an overview of the changes that have been made recently.

* June 2024: We made changes to clarify and provide more detail about the information we may collect through your interactions with us. We also made changes to better explain how we leverage cookies, pixels, web beacons, tags, scripts and other website technology, and how system apps on certain devices operate. Finally, we consolidated descriptions of similar state laws to make the state law section easier to navigate and use, and we added information about new privacy laws in Oregon and Texas.
* January 2024: We updated two links for Safelink customers.
* December 2023: We made changes to the state privacy law section of our privacy policy to clarify and provide additional details about our collection, use and sharing practices and to add information about the Utah privacy law. We also updated the policy to provide additional detail about the cookies, pixels, tags, and other technologies that are on our websites and apps, about the collection of pictures in certain locations to prevent fraud, and about the collection of location information for network management purposes. We also added information about our use of automation and the collection of information from third parties.

### **Introduction**

Our Privacy Policy describes the information that we collect, how it’s used, shared, and retained, your choices about how it’s used and shared, and your rights under certain privacy laws. This policy applies to all TracFone brands including Total by Verizon, Straight Talk Wireless, Tracfone, Simple Mobile, SafeLink Wireless, Walmart Family Mobile, Net10 Wireless, Page Plus, GoSmart Mobile, and Clearway Wireless for Business. TracFone is a Verizon company.

When you use our websites and services you are subject to this Policy and the terms and conditions of the service associated with your brand. We do not require you to provide personal information to us to enjoy some of our services. However, if you do not provide certain personal information, you may not be able to use or access portions of our websites, such as the account features or account information.

### **Categories and Types of Personal Information We Collect**

We, and service providers acting on our behalf, collect information when you purchase and use our products and services and when you interact with us. Depending on the products and services you use, the personal information we collect may include:

* Contact, billing and other information you provide such as your name, nickname, address, email, phone numbers, images, voice recordings or voiceprints, other biometric identifiers, date of birth, driver’s license, signature, other information needed to process payment, Social Security Number or Tax Identification Number, and information you provide in device setup, surveys and TracFone-sponsored promotions, and grant or job applications.
* Identifiers that link to your account or device.
* Commercial and transaction information related to your payment method, credit card information, including account numbers, card holder names and addresses, phone or device purchases, airtime card purchases or redemptions, wireless plans and offers, activation and port-in history, wireless device loan repayment history and metrics, other financial information and records, and products or services you purchase or place into your online cart.
* How you use our services and your devices, which may include: call records containing phone numbers you call and receive calls from, websites you visit, text records, wireless location, application and feature usage, rewards program activity, product and device-specific information and identifiers, router connections, domain name server information, service options you choose, mobile and device numbers, technical configuration and other similar information. When you grant them permission, our mobile apps may also collect Wi-Fi, Global Positioning Satellite (GPS) and other location information.
* Our cloud apps may backup your contact list, call records containing phone numbers you call and receive calls from, text records, text messages, your photo and video library, documents and music when you grant us the required permissions. In addition, depending on your mobile device operating system, we may obtain your permission to collect location information for scheduled backups or to locate printing vendors near you. Additionally, we maintain several internet websites and mobile apps to inform you about plans and services, and help complete transactions. As part of this, we may collect certain information including browsing history, search history, interaction with our websites and apps, and interaction with advertisements.
* Network and device information including how our network and your devices are working. We monitor the conditions of the network you are using such as traffic flow, speed, capacity, power, and environmental, as well as temperature and operating status of home network equipment such as your fixed wireless equipment. We collect location information about your wireless device including cell tower location information. This also includes how you use or access our service or websites such as Wi-Fi usage, IP address, internet browser, operating system, geographic locations, the domain name of the website and/or Internet Service Provider (ISP) from which you are linked to our websites, the model of the phone that you are using, your device identifier (UDID), web browsing and wireless application use information, date and time stamp, clickstream data to analyze trends in aggregate to administer our websites, and websites performance information. We may also collect aggregated network strength data. This data may combine geolocation information, signal data, and other information to help us monitor the strength and reliability of the services we provide to our customers.
* Demographic and interest information from third parties or from you to verify your identity or determine your eligibility for certain services. This may include age or date of birth, gender, marital status, disability, or military or veteran status. For example, this information may be required as part of the Federal Lifeline program to determine a customer’s qualification for SafeLink. We may ask you to provide a copy of your driver’s license to verify your identity.
* Educational, professional, and employment information if you submit it as part of verifying your eligibility for our Lifeline program. For example, you may elect to verify your income by submitting pay stubs.
* Information when you visit our sites and use our apps, including through cookies and similar technology. This includes your IP address, mobile number, device and advertising identifiers; browser and platform type, operating system, connection speed and other attributes; pages that you visit before and after visiting our sites; the date and time of your visit; information about the links you click and pages you view within the sites and screen records.
* Information when you contact us, seek technical support, or enter a TracFone-sponsored contest, sweepstake or promotion. When you contact us or we contact you, we and our vendors may monitor or record that communication for quality assurance, to train or support employees, resources or systems, and security purposes. We may also collect information when you contact us on social media, open emails we send or interact with our ads, or register to receive news or updates.
* TracFone always seeks to provide the best service, products, and selections to our customers. We may create customer profiles from information we obtain from third parties and develop inferences such as your preferences, predispositions, and behaviors. We use this to better develop products, services and offers, and to market to you.

If a child or other beneficiary is the qualifying recipient for the Lifeline Assistance Program, we will also collect the child’s or other beneficiary’s name, date of birth, and partial Social Security number to verify their eligibility in the program.

### **How We Collect Personal Information**

We collect information from you when you interact with us and use our products and services, including information about how you use these products and services and our websites, when you make a purchase, or when you establish or modify an online account. We also collect information when you interact with our customer service representatives or use our websites or apps to place an order or ask questions about your account or service; seek technical support; contact us on social media; enter a TracFone-sponsored or affiliate contest; participate in surveys, sweepstakes or promotions; refer a friend or respond to a referral; or participate in our rewards program. When you communicate with us, we may monitor or record the interaction to help us better serve you; to personalize your experiences; to train or otherwise support employees, resources or systems; and for fraud detection and security purposes. We may use artificial intelligence guided by humans, such as chat bots, to respond to your inquiry. When you interact with us through third-party services like Facebook Messenger or Twitter Direct Message, your communications are also governed by these companies’ privacy policies.

Some devices may have pre-installed applications that are used by us and our partners to:

* Collect information about network and device conditions such as network strengths, performance, coverage, and quality.
* Automatically install apps or software when you activate your device, during certain operating system upgrades and with your consent at later times, for example, when you request an app from an advertisement. The software may also update apps that it installed on your device or when you otherwise permit it. These apps collect information when an app we place is first opened or is uninstalled, device identifiers, features and software version on your device, and they may send you notifications about offers and promotions from TracFone brands and other third parties that may interest you. You can use your device app controls to disable notifications in Mobile Services Manager to opt out of notifications.

Some apps installed or updated on your device in this way do not appear as icons on your device screen because of their limited utility. For example, they might facilitate the download of apps you select for your device, update apps you already have on your device, or report to an app owner that an app has been opened on the device. You can see and also delete or disable apps installed on your device, whether or not they have visible icons, using your device’s Application Manager under Settings. Apps on your device are governed by their own terms and privacy policies.

We, our vendors, and third party companies, collect information from our sites and apps for operational purposes such as improving website and app security, authenticating you, detecting and deterring fraud, improving site performance and providing content and analytics. We and these vendors and third-party companies may use cookies, pixels, web beacons, tags, scripts or similar technologies\[1\] on our pages and the browsers you use and may access advertising identifiers from your mobile device operating systems.

We also collect information from third parties. This includes demographic and interest data as well as device type, carrier, city and state information from third party data providers; information from social media platforms when you interact with us via social media or use your social media login to interact with TracFone sites or offers; contact, marketing lead, and other information we purchase or receive; and fraud information.

We also allow third-party advertising companies to collect information about your activity on our websites and in our app, for example through cookies, mobile ad identifiers, pixels, web beacons, application programming interfaces (APIs) and social network plugins, to help us provide more relevant TracFone advertisements on our website and on others’ sites and apps. These ads may be tailored for you based on your activity on our sites and combined with your activities on other websites and in apps where these advertising companies are present. These advertising companies may also use information they collect for others’ advertising purposes. The use of information collected about your visits over time and across different websites, apps and devices is known as cross-context behavioral, or interest-based, advertising.

### **How We Use Personal Information**

TracFone uses personal information to:

* Deliver and maintain products and services and collect and process transactions
* Establish and maintain your account, payment and claim filing purposes, where applicable, and to provide the auto-refill program
* Anticipate and resolve problems with your service and provide account-related services
* Help you with service and technical support issues or questions
* Detect and prevent fraud
* Comply with legal requirements
* Communicate with you
* Manage, administer and improve our websites and services, and website and and app security
* Auditing and accounting purposes
* Inform you of products and services that better meet your needs
* Assess credit and payment risk
* Manage and protect our services, employees and users
* Personalize our services and your experiences and make our marketing more relevant to you
* Research, develop and market new products and services
* Authenticate you
* Determine your eligibility for new products and services
* Better predict and deliver content and marketing offers that may interest you
* Measure service quality

_Analytics_. We use mobile analytics software to better understand the functionalities of our mobile software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use an application, the events that occur within an application, aggregated usage, performance data, and location where an application was downloaded. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within a mobile application.

_Automated Processing._ We may use automated techniques including artificial intelligence to assist us with these uses. For example, we may use machine learning techniques with information we have about you and other customers to provide you with more relevant marketing messages or predict what services might most interest you.

_De-identified and aggregated information_. We may also de-identify or aggregate information so that we or our affiliates may use it for business and marketing purposes. For example, the data we aggregate might be used to analyze, personalize and improve our services. We may de-identify your CPNI and, if we do so, we will maintain and use the data in a non-individually identifiable form and will not attempt to re-identify the data.

### **How We Share Personal Information**

**We share information within TracFone and other Verizon companies.**

We share information within TracFone and with other Verizon companies for a variety of purposes, including providing you the latest information about our products and services and offering you our latest promotions. You can limit the sharing of Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI), which relates to the type, quantity, destination, technical configuration, location, amount of use and related billing information of your wireless services; and certain credit information, such as credit scores, your account and payment history and information in your consumer reports; with other Verizon companies for marketing services to you that are different from the ones you already have. Your choices about our use and sharing of CPNI and credit information are described in the “Your choices about how information is used” section of this Policy.

**We share information with service providers and partners.**

We share information with service providers. We use service providers to perform services on our behalf, such as marketing, fulfillment services, shipping to customers and to help us offer, provide, repair, restore and bill for services. We require that service providers protect and restrict use of personal information consistent with the terms described in this Policy. Your wireless number may be shared for text messaging services operated by service providers. These service providers may directly contact you on our behalf by text messages with promotions, discounts, advertisements, reminders related to your services, or other information that may be helpful or informative to you. You can opt out of these messages using the mechanism provided.

We share information that identifies you with a partner who verifies your identity to facilitate your interactions with third parties, such as banks. Our partner also uses the information we share to assist third parties with decisions about credit applications that you submitted to a bank or other third party. Information about how to opt out of the disclosure of information for this purpose is in the “Your Choices About How Information is Used” section.

We may share with or we may allow our service providers to collect personal information, including your activity on our sites and in our apps. These companies may use technologies, such as cookies, pixels, web beacons, tags, scripts, or similar technologies\[2\] on our pages and the browsers you use. These service providers help us improve website and app security, authenticate you, detect and deter fraud, improve site performance, provide content or analytics, and other purposes as described in the “How we collect personal information” section.

_Walmart Family Mobile Customers_. If you are a Walmart Family Mobile customer, we work with Walmart Stores, Inc. ("Walmart") to offer the Walmart Family Mobile service. Any information you provide directly to Walmart will be subject to Walmart's Privacy Policy, not this one. This includes information you provide to Walmart in connection with your device purchase, upgrade, return, or replacement, whether in its stores, by phone or online, including but not limited to, if you purchase a Family Mobile device or obtain technical support for the device at or from Walmart or its agents. In addition, if you activate Walmart Family Mobile communications services at a Walmart store, Walmart may request personal information from you that is passed to TracFone as part of the activation process, but which may also be retained by Walmart. You can learn more by [visiting Walmart's Privacy Policy](https://corporate.walmart.com/privacy-security/walmart-privacy-policy).

_Software Application for Our Websites_. TracFone also works with other companies who supply software applications for use on our websites. The software is used to collect survey or feedback information or support real-time chat sessions from customers who visit our websites and utilize these tools. Information from your web session, including your device serial number, phone number, and account email may be associated with your responses when you use these tools. This information is used by TracFone exclusively for analysis of survey or feedback results and will not be shared with any third party for any other purposes.

When you purchase or use services that are offered jointly by TracFone and one of our partners, both parties may receive information. When this is the case, you should also review the partner company’s privacy policy because it may describe uses of information that are different from ours.

We also share de-identified information with companies to assist with the delivery of advertising campaigns or aggregate reports.

**We share information with advertising companies.**

We may share, or allow certain third-party advertising companies to collect information about your activity on our sites and in our apps, including advertising identifiers from your mobile device operating system. They can use that information to help us provide more relevant TracFone advertising on our own and other sites and apps. These companies may combine information from our sites with similar information they collect on other sites to determine whether you fit into an audience that advertisers, including TracFone, are trying to reach, to serve targeted advertising to you on our sites and other sites and platforms, or to find other potential customers. To do this, we and these companies use technologies, such as cookies, pixels, web beacons, tags, scripts, or similar technologies\[3\] on our pages and the browsers you use, or we may share information using application program interfaces (APIs).

TracFone sites and services may also include social networks or other third-party plug-ins and widgets that may provide information to their associated social networks or third parties even if you do not click on or otherwise interact with the plug-ins and widgets

Our customers and website visitors can limit the sale and sharing of personal information as well as the use of this information for certain types of targeted advertising. Certain states give consumers who reside in those states the right to make these opt out choices. Please visit the “Your choices about how information is used\[4\]” section of this policy to learn how to opt out.

We also share de-identified information with companies to assist with the delivery of advertising campaigns or aggregate reports.

**Additional ways we may share information.**

We may further share customer personal information in the following situations:

* With third parties, including government and law enforcement entities; to protect our rights and property; to protect against fraudulent, malicious, abusive, unauthorized or unlawful use of our products or services; and to protect our network, services, devices and users from such;
* To comply with valid legal process including subpoenas, court orders or search warrants, and as otherwise authorized by law;
* With the appropriate government and law enforcement entities, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect your safety or the safety of others or in other emergencies;
* To advance or defend against complaints or legal claims in court, administrative proceedings or elsewhere;
* When needed by outside auditors or regulators;
* With necessary third parties in connection with, or during negotiations for, a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets;
* With social media companies when you choose to interact with us through those companies as information about your account may be discussed during those interactions;
* If you are referred to TracFone by your Health Maintenance Organization (HMO), we share your mobile number with the HMO provider. and
* With your consent.

### **Your choices about how information is used.**

You have choices about how we reach you with marketing offers and about how we use certain information we have about you.

We may send you emails regarding promotional offers or other news. You can choose not to receive our email direct marketing communications at any time by opting-out or unsubscribing. You can do this by clicking on the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of every email promotion we deliver. Upon such election, we will not email you directly with promotional messages, though you may see marketing messages from TracFone in other forms and directed at a general audience.

You can limit the sharing of CPNI and credit information within TracFone and with its affiliates for marketing services to you that are different from the ones you have.

* StraightTalk Customers: [https://www.straighttalk.com/cpni-amr](https://www.straighttalk.com/cpni-amr)
* Tracfone Customers: [https://www.tracfone.com/cpni-amr](https://www.tracfone.com/cpni-amr)
* Total by Verizon Customers: [https://www.totalbyverizon.com/cpni-amr](https://www.totalbyverizon.com/cpni-amr)
* Net10 Customers: [https://www.net10wireless.com/cpni-amr](https://www.net10wireless.com/cpni-amr)
* Other Customers: We will not share CPNI or credit information within Verizon for them to market services that are different from the ones you have without giving you an opportunity to opt out.

You can limit the sale and sharing of website information, as well as the use of this information for certain targeted advertising. You can opt out by visiting the Your Privacy Choices page at the bottom of your brand’s website. This page also describes how we honor [Global Privacy Control](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) signals you may set on your browser. We do not respond to Do Not Track signals.

You can also use the Your Privacy Choices page at the bottom of your brand’s website to opt out of the disclosure of information to our partner who verifies your identity to facilitate your interactions with third parties, such as banks. Our partner also uses the information we share to assist third parties with decisions about credit applications that you submitted to a bank or other third party.

You can opt out of interest-based advertising on mobile apps on your mobile device. Apple devices allow apps to include interest-based advertising only if you opt in using the app’s pop-up notice. You can change your choice using Apple device settings. On Android devices, you can opt out using your device setting to “Opt out of Ads Personalization”. You can also manage cookies using features and functions available on most Internet browsers that allow you to delete or disable cookies and even choose what types of cookies may be placed on your device. Please be aware that disabling cookies may prevent you from using specific features on our sites and other sites, such as ordering products or services and maintaining an online account. Please note that some of the controls described above are device or browser-based. You will need to record your choices on each device or browser where you want them to be in place. In addition, your opt-outs may be stored via cookies. If you clear your cookies, please check to make sure your opt-outs are in place. More information about cookie controls for specific browsers can be found here:

If you allow it, our apps may collect your precise geolocation. The app uses this information for the purposes described when at the time you granted permission. You may opt out at any time by changing the location settings for the apps you use on your mobile device.

Our apps may also request permission to send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you do not wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off using your device controls.

### **How We Secure and Retain Personal Information**

We use administrative, organizational, technical, and physical safeguards to protect against the unauthorized access to, use or disclosure of information we collect or store. In addition, we train our employees on the importance of privacy and security, as well as the proper ways to access, use and disclose customer information. Our practices and policies prohibit employees with whom we share this information from using sensitive information unless they are authorized to do so and have a business need.

We retain personal information as long as it is needed for business, tax, audit, investigative, security and/or legal purposes and then securely delete or destroy them. We incorporate personal information into different types of records, not always by distinct data elements. For example, your name may be part of your account, billing, technical support and call detail records.

Although we strive to keep information secure, we can’t guarantee that our safeguards will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use or disclose personal information. If you become aware of a security issue, please contact us at privacy@tracfone.com.

### **Links to Other Websites**

_Third-Party Links_. Our websites may contain links to other websites that are not owned, operated, or controlled by us. Any personal information collected by such third-party websites is not governed by this Policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy policies of such third-party websites prior to submitting any personal information.

Advertisements may appear on pages throughout our websites. Some advertisements may request information directly from you or provide links to take you to websites that may request personal information. We have no control over these advertisers' privacy policies, so we encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company advertising on our websites prior to submitting any personal information.

_Third-Party Websites_. In some instances, our websites’ content is also featured on other websites with differing or non-existent privacy policies. These websites may collect personal information from website visitors that may or may not be used in conjunction with our website information. Prior to supplying personal information to any third-party company linking to our website, please read and understand their privacy policies.

### **Policy Regarding Information Obtained from Children**

Our websites are not structured to attract children under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect information, directly or passively, from children under the age of 18. Ordering online products and services from TracFone is limited to adults (ages 18+). Of course, wireless devices and services purchased for family use may be used by minors without our knowledge. If that happens, any information collected from the usage will appear to be the personal information of the adult subscriber and treated as such under this Policy.

### **Public Forums/Blogs**

Our websites may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. You should not provide personally identifiable information in any publicly accessible blog or community forum.

To request removal of personal information from our blogs and forums, contact us at privacy@tracfone.com, and we will do our best to comply with the request. In some cases, we may not be able to remove personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### **Refer-A-Friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our websites, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address and automatically generate a one-time email to send your friend inviting them to visit the site. If you use the “Import Contacts” feature, we may collect your friends’ names and addresses in order to administer TracFone’s Refer-A-Friend program. We do not store your friend's information or use it for any other purpose.

### **Gift Purchases**

If you purchase a gift, we will ask you for the recipient’s name and mailing address in order to ship the product to the individual. We do not retain the recipient’s information or use it for any other purpose.

### **How Customers and Visitors Can Access and Update Personal Information**

You can verify your account and manage personal information, including deleting or changing certain personal information, by logging into your account on our website and going to the account profile or account information section.

If you are unable to log into your account, please contact a customer care agent by calling 1-800-867-7183. All requests for changes or deletion of account information require account verification by answering security questions or providing the Personal Identification Number (PIN) you set when you first activated your account.

In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain personal information, or may need to retain personal information in order to continue providing a service.

### **California**

The California Consumer Privacy Act, or CCPA, gives you specific rights as a California resident. The law provides you with the right to know what information we collect about you and how we use it; to access, delete, and correct that information within certain limitations; to tell us not to sell or share personal information about you; to limit the use of certain sensitive personal information; and to not be discriminated against for invoking these rights.

**Your Right to Know**
----------------------

We describe the personal information we collect and how we use it in this Privacy Policy. As detailed above in “How We Collect Personal Information,” we collect information from you when you interact with us and use our products and services.

Depending on what products and services you use and how you interact with us, we may collect these categories of personal information, some of which may be considered sensitive personal information under California law:

* Identifiers, including name, physical and email address, mobile device identifiers, IP address, account credentials, and other similar identifiers;
* Personal information that reveals your Social Security, driver’s license, state identification card, or passport number;
* Account log-in, financial account, debit card, or credit card number;
* Characteristics of legally protected classifications, such as race and gender, if you provide them to us;
* Commercial information, such as products or services you purchase and financial information;
* Biometric information, for example, some stores use facial recognition authentication to prevent fraud;
* Internet or other electronic network activity information, including browsing and search history on our sites; information regarding your interactions with us through our websites, applications, advertisements, and social media; and your rewards program activity;
* Geolocation data, including precise geolocation data from our apps when you permit it;
* Audio, electronic, visual or similar information, such as voice recordings of customer service calls;
* Professional or employment-related information;
* Demographic and interest data as well as device type, carrier, city and state information from third party data providers;
* Inferences drawn from any of the information described above to create a profile reflecting your preferences, characteristics, predispositions, and behavior;
* Secure Account Information including account log-in, financial account, debit card, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credentials allowing access to an account; and
* Other information that may identify, relate to, describe, or is capable of being associated with you.

Our policies require that we retain records for as long they are needed for legal, tax, audit, investigative, and/or security purposes and then securely delete or destroy them. We incorporate personal information into different types of records, not always by distinct data elements. For example, your name could be part of your customer account record, transaction record, or call records. Each type of record may be retained for a different time period depending on its purpose. We have established criteria for how long to keep different types of records.

We, and our affiliates, use the information we collect for business and commercial purposes as defined by the CCPA. Business and commercial purposes include providing services to you; communicating with you and providing customer service; personalizing your experiences; improving our services; providing marketing and advertising; debugging; auditing our processes and services; short-term transient uses; research; and security, fraud, and legal compliance purposes.

Service providers may use information for the same purposes, as necessary for them to perform work for us (including in the last twelve months). Service providers are required to protect the information we share with them or they collect on our behalf and use it only for the specific purposes that we allow. We may also disclose information to third parties, such as partners and to law enforcement, among others, as detailed elsewhere in this policy.

We share information that identifies you with a partner who facilitates your interactions with third parties, including for verifying your identity and providing information to assist with a decision on a credit application you have submitted to a bank or other third party.

We also allow select third parties to directly collect information about your activity on our websites and in our apps using cookies, mobile ad identifiers, pixels, web beacons, social network plugins and similar technologies to inform our and others’ cross contextual advertising. These activities may be considered selling or sharing personal information under California law. For information about how to opt out of these activities, and to learn more about TracFone’s selling and sharing activities, please visit our “Your Privacy Choices” pages linked in the “Your Right to Opt Out of Selling and Sharing Personal Information” section below. We do not knowingly sell or share personal information related to children under 16 years of age.

Some of the information that we collect is Sensitive Personal Information under California Law. California law defines sensitive personal information as:

* Information that reveals your Social Security, driver’s license, state identification card, or passport number;
* Account log-in, financial account, debit card, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credentials allowing access to an account;
* Precise geolocation;
* Racial or ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, or union membership;
* Contents of your mail, email and text messages unless we are the intended recipient of the communication;
* Genetic data;
* Using biometric information to uniquely identify a consumer; and
* Collecting and analyzing personal information about your health, sex life or sexual orientation.

We do not use, sell, share, or disclose sensitive personal information for any purpose other than to provide the goods or services requested by you, with your consent, or for other purposes expressly authorized by California law, such as to detect security incidents.

**Your Right to Access and Correct Information**
------------------------------------------------

You have the right to request access to specific pieces and categories of personal information we collect about you. You may submit these requests as described below under “How to Submit Your Privacy Rights Request.” We will honor at least two access rights requests every twelve months as required by California law. To the extent technically feasible, we will provide this information to you in a portable and readily usable format. You also can request that we correct inaccurate personal information we have about you.

**Your Right to Delete**
------------------------

You have the right to request that we delete personal information we have about you. We are unable to delete information that is necessary to provide you ongoing service, for security purposes, that we are contractually obligated to retain, or that is necessary to comply with legal obligations. You or your authorized agent may submit a request to delete. Instructions on how to submit this request can be found below under “How to Submit Your CCPA Request.”

**Your Right to Opt Out of the Sale and Sharing of Personal Information**
-------------------------------------------------------------------------

California consumers have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of personal information. The term “sale or sharing” is broadly defined to include sharing personal information for monetary or other valuable consideration and the sharing of personal information for cross contextual advertising purposes, but does not cover all sharing of personal information. We do not knowingly include the personal information of consumers under 16 years of age in this selling or sharing.

Our activities that fall under the definition of “sale or share” in the CCPA are:

* sharing information that identifies you with a partner who facilitates your interactions with third parties, including for verifying your identity and providing information to assist with a decision on a credit application you have submitted to a bank or other third party;
* using third-party advertising companies’ cookies, pixels, tags, and other web technologies on our site to collect information about your activity on our site and apps during your visit which can be used and combined with other information about you from your activity and behavior across unaffiliated websites and apps to tailor the ads you see from us and others;
* sharing consumer information to third-party advertising and social media companies to help them better target our advertising on their websites and applications and to help find other potential customers using interest segments and audiences they create from your activities across non-affiliated websites and apps; and
* using consumer information we obtain from third-parties to better customize our advertising, when that information is derived from your activities across non-affiliated sites, apps, services and businesses.

To opt out of the selling and sharing of personal information, including for identify verification and credit inquiry purposes, please visit our Your Privacy Choices pages, available at:

* Tracfone: [https://www.tracfone.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.tracfone.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)
* StraightTalk: [https://www.straighttalk.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.straighttalk.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)
* Simple Mobile: [https://www.simplemobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.simplemobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)
* Net10 Wireless: [https://www.net10wireless.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.net10wireless.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)
* Walmart Family Mobile: [https://www.myfamilymobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.myfamilymobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)
* Total by Verizon: [https://www.totalbyverizon.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.totalbyverizon.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)
* Safelink: [https://www.safelinkwireless.com/en/#!/ypc](https://www.safelinkwireless.com/en/#!/ypc)
* Go Smart Mobile: [https://www.gosmartmobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns](https://www.gosmartmobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns)

We also recognize that you are exercising your choice to opt out if you engage a browser-based [Global Privacy Control](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) (GPC) when visiting our sites. If you are not logged in or don’t have an account and use a GPC on your visit, we will apply your choice to stop third-party cookies, pixels, and other similar technology on our sites from collecting, using, and sharing information about you from your visit to our website for purposes of tailoring ads to you, from us and others, based on your online behavior and activity. You will be opted out of sharing activity while you are on our sites whenever you have your GPC turned on, but we need more information from you to identify you and apply your opt out of selling and sharing to your phone and email information.

If you are a member who is logged in to your account when using the GPC signal to opt out, we will apply your choice to block third-party ad technology, and we will also opt you out of any selling and sharing of personal information associated with your account.

Clearway Wireless for Business does not sell or share personal information.

**Your Right to Limit the Use of Sensitive Personal Information**

You have the right to ask us to limit the use and disclosure of sensitive personal information if we use that information for purposes beyond what is needed to provide the products and services you request or for other reasons specified in the law. We use or disclose sensitive personal information only for purposes allowable in the law or with your consent so we do not offer you an option to limit the use of sensitive personal information. The purposes for which we might use sensitive personal information include: detecting security incidents; resisting malicious, deceptive, fraudulent or illegal actions; ensuring the physical safety of a person; short-term, transient uses; performing services such as maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, fulfilling orders and transactions; verifying personal information; and verifying, maintaining or enhancing a service on a device that is owned manufactured or controlled by us or on your device. We may also share personal information with service providers providing storage or similar services on our behalf.

**Your Right to Not Be Discriminated Against**

We do not discriminate against you if you exercise any rights described in this section. We will not deny goods or services, charge different prices or rates for goods or services, or provide you a different level or quality of goods and services. You also have the right to receive information about the financial incentives that we offer to you.

**How to Submit Your CCPA Request**
-----------------------------------

If you wish to exercise your right to access, delete, or correct personal information, you or your authorized agent can make a request through your existing online account. If you do not have an existing account, you can submit a request by calling 1-877-799-1999 or submitting a request online at:

If you are a representative of a Clearway Wireless for Business customer and wish to submit a CCPA request, you can submit a request by calling 1-844-638-1028.

We may require you to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. For example, you may have to prove access to your mobile phone or to an email address you provided to us.

You can learn how to exercise your right to opt out of the sale and sharing of personal information above under “Your Right to Opt Out of the Sale and Sharing of Personal Information.”

We will endeavor to respond to your requests within 45 days, but it may take up to 90 days. If we need more than 45 days, we will contact you to let you know that we need additional time.
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**Reporting**
-------------

California law requires businesses to report annually on the number of privacy requests they receive each year. TracFone received the following requests from consumers in 2023. Employee and contractor requests are included in [Verizon’s numbers](https://privacy.verizon.com/about/privacy/ccpa-reporting).

|     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
|     | **Request to Delete** | **Request to Know** | **Request to Correct** | **Do Not Sell, Share, & Target** |
| **Total Requests** | 802 | 4832 | 458 | 102,148 |
| **Complied With** | 789 | 4698 | 458 | 101,598 |
| **Denied** | 13  | 134 | N/A | 550 |
| **Average Response Time (Days)** | 17  | 19  | <1  | <2  |

**Other California Privacy Rights**
-----------------------------------

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 entitles California consumers to request, once per year, that we disclose the identity of any third parties to whom we have shared personal information for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you wish to submit a request, you may write to us at privacy@tracfone.com or call us at 1-877-799-1999.

**Questions**

If you have questions about your rights under California law or about our privacy policies and practices, email us at [privacy@tracfone.com](mailto:privacy@tracfone.com).

**Colorado, Connecticut, Oregon, Texas, Utah and Virginia**

Colorado, Connecticut, Oregon, Texas, Utah and Virginia have comprehensive privacy laws that provide residents with additional specific rights.

**Your right to know what personal information we collect, how we use and share it, and how long we keep it.** This privacy policy provides details about our collection and use practices. The state laws generally require that we provide you information about the categories of personal information we collect and the purposes for which we collect each category. This includes:

* Contact and device information (including name, physical and email address, mobile device identifiers, IP address, account credentials, other similar identifiers); commercial information such as products and services you purchase or consider and financial information; internet or electronic network activity (including browsing history, search history on our site, information regarding our interactions with our websites, applications and advertisements, and your rewards program activity); contact, marketing lead, and other information we purchase or receive; fraud information; information from social media platforms when you interact with us via social media or use your social media login to interact with TracFone sites or offers; and demographic and interest data as well as device type, carrier, city and state information from third party data providers. We use this information to provide our products and services, operate our businesses, communicate with you and provide customer service; personalize your experiences; improve our services; provide marketing and advertising; create business insights; debug problems, audit our processes and services; short-term transient uses; research; and security, fraud, and legal compliance.
* Geolocation data, including precise geolocation data from our apps when you permit it. We use this information for purposes including business operations; security and fraud protection and prevention; to personalize your experiences and our marketing; and for the specific purposes we describe to you when you opt in to the collection of precise geolocation data from our apps.
* Biometric information. Some stores use facial recognition authentication to prevent fraud.
* Demographic and interest information you provide or we obtain from third parties and inferences drawn from information reflecting your preferences, characteristics, predispositions and behaviors. We use this information to help us better understand our customers and our markets, personalize your experiences, provide marketing and advertising, test for bias and create business insights.
* Secure Account Information including account log-in, Social Security number, driver’s license, state identification card, passport number, professional or employment related information, financial account, debit card, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credentials allowing access to an account. We use this to provide you with access to your account, accept payment for products and services you purchase, confirm eligibility for certain services, security and fraud prevention and legal compliance purposes.
* Audio, electronic, visual or similar information, such as voice recordings of customer service calls and photographs of you and customer equipment. We use this information to troubleshoot service, to improve our service and for quality assurance, help us better understand our customers and our markets, personalize your experiences, authenticate you, security and fraud prevention, provide marketing and advertising, test for bias and create business insights.
* Other information that may identify, relate to, describe, or is capable of being associated with you. For example, we may collect your insurance policy number to process damage claims.

Some of the information we collect is considered sensitive personal information under the state laws. The laws describe sensitive data to include some or all of the following: personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, national origin, religious beliefs, mental or physical health condition or diagnosis, sex life or sexual orientation, status as transgender or nonbinary, citizenship or immigration status; processing genetic or biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying you; personal data collected from a known child; precise geolocation information; or status as a crime victim.

We collect personal information when you interact with us and use our products and services, from certain third-party sources and from the devices you use. You may interact with us in different ways, for example, when you place an order or have questions about your account or services; contact us on social media; seek technical support; or enter a TracFone-sponsored or affiliated contest, sweepstakes or promotion.

We retain information only as long as reasonably necessary for business, accounting, tax or legal purposes and then securely delete it.

Third parties we use to do work on our behalf may use information for the same purposes. We share information with service providers (also known as processors) as necessary for them to perform work for us. They are required to protect the information they receive from us or collect on our behalf and use it only for the specific purposes that we allow. We may also share information with others with your consent and as further described in other sections of this policy.

We also may share information that identifies you with a partner who uses it to assist in your interactions with third parties. First, we may share personal information collected about you to confirm your identity when you are transacting with or signing into a third party service, such as your bank. Second, we may share personal information collected about you with third parties you are attempting to do business with to help make a credit decision on an application for service that you have submitted to a third party. This activity may be a sale of personal information under the state laws. We also allow select third parties to directly collect information about your activity on our websites and in our apps using cookies, mobile ad identifiers, pixels, web beacons, social network plugins and similar technologies to inform our and others’ cross contextual advertising. This activity may be considered targeted advertising under the state laws. For information about how to opt out of these activities, and to learn more about TracFone’s selling and targeted advertising activities, please visit our “Your Privacy Choices” pages links in the “Your Right to Opt Out of Selling Personal Information and Targeted Advertising” section below. We do not knowingly sell or share personal information related to children under 16 years of age.

**Your rights to access and correct information.** You can access specific pieces and categories of personal information we collect as described below under “How to Submit Your Privacy Rights Request.” To the extent technically feasible, we will provide this information to you in a portable and readily usable format. You also can request that we correct inaccurate personal information we have about you.

**Your right to delete information.** You can request that we delete personal information we have unless we need it for reasons specified in the privacy laws. Privacy laws describe these reasons slightly differently, but generally, they include: needing the information to provide the services you use and the internal operations needed to maintain an ongoing business relationship or perform a contract with you, maintaining information security, preventing fraud, and exercising our legal rights including defending against legal claims, complying with laws and cooperating with law enforcement in good faith. If you would like us to delete, you or your authorized agent may submit a request to delete. Instructions on how to submit this request can be found below under “How to Submit Your Privacy Rights Request.

**Use of sensitive personal information.**These state laws prohibit us from using sensitive personal information without your consent, except as specified in the law. The reasons vary slightly within different Privacy laws, but generally include: complying with laws, rules, regulations, investigative subpoena or summons by governmental authorities; cooperating with law enforcement; investigating, establishing, preparing or defending against legal claims; providing and maintaining the products and services you use, preventing and responding to security and other significant incidents; taking immediate steps to protect an interest that is essential for the life or physical safety; and using information for short-term transient purposes such as displaying relevant information to you based on your activity during a single interaction. We only use sensitive personal information as authorized by the law or after we obtain your express consent.

**Your right to tell us not to use personal information to create profiles about you that we use to inform decisions that have legal or similarly significant effects.** We do not use personal information to profile you to further decisions that have legal or similar significant effects.

**Your right to tell us not to sell personal information or process it for certain targeted advertising purposes.** The laws vary in the way they define sale and certain targeted advertising, but generally, they require that we provide you with the ability to limit activities that involve sharing personal information for monetary or other valuable consideration and using personal information about you from your activity across other websites or apps to target ads to you. The definitions do not cover all sharing of personal information. We do not knowingly sell personal information related to children under 16 years of age.

Our activity that falls under the definition of “sale” or “targeted advertising” under these state laws is:

* disclosing information that identifies you with a partner who facilitates your interactions with third parties, including for verifying your identity and providing information to assist with a decision on a credit application you have submitted to a bank or other third party;
* using third-party advertising companies’ cookies, pixels, tags, and other web technologies on our site to collect information about your activity on our site and apps during your visit which can be used and combined with other information about you from your activity and behavior across unaffiliated websites and apps to tailor the ads you see from us and others;
* disclosing consumer information to third-party advertising and social media companies to help them better target our advertising on their websites and applications and to help find other potential customers using interest segments and audiences they create from your activities across non-affiliated websites and apps; and
* using consumer information we obtain from third-parties to better customize our advertising, when that information is derived from your activities across non-affiliated sites and apps.

To opt out of the sale of personal information, including for identity verification and credit inquiry purposes, and the processing of personal information for targeted advertising please visit our Your Privacy Choices pages, available at:

We also recognize that you are exercising your choice to opt out if you engage a browser-based [Global Privacy Control](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) (GPC) when visiting our sites. If you are not logged in or don’t have an account and use a GPC on your visit, we will apply your choice to stop third-party cookies, pixels, and other similar technology on our sites from collecting, using, and sharing information about you from your visit to our website for purposes of tailoring ads to you, from us and others, based on your online behavior and activity. You will be opted out of sharing activity while you are on our sites whenever you have your GPC turned on, but we need more information from you to identify you and apply your opt out of selling and sharing to your phone and email information.

If you are a member who is logged in to your account when using the GPC signal to opt out, we will apply your choice to block third-party ad technology, and we will also opt you out of any selling and sharing of personal information associated with your account.

**Some states allow you to appeal** a denial of your request to exercise the privacy rights provided by the state law. If you are a resident of Colorado, Connecticut, Oregon, Texas, or Virginia and we deny your request, we will notify you and you may submit an appeal using a link we provide. You also may submit an appeal of a decision we have made regarding your privacy rights by emailing us at privacy@tracfone.com. When submitting your appeal through email, use the word "APPEAL" in your subject line and provide your name, contact information including phone number, a description of the decision you are appealing, and the reason for your appeal.

**You have the right to not be discriminated against.** We do not discriminate against you if you exercise any rights provided to you by state law. We will not deny goods or services, charge different prices or rates for goods or services or provide you a different level or quality of goods and services. You also have the right to receive information about any financial incentives we offer to you.

**How to Submit Your Privacy Rights Request**
---------------------------------------------

If you wish to exercise your right to access, delete, or correct personal information, you can make a request through your existing online account. You, if you do not have an existing account, or your authorized agent can submit a request by calling 1-877-799-1999 or submitting a request online at:

We may require you to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. For example, you may have to prove access to your mobile phone or to an email address you provided to us.

You can learn how to exercise your right to opt out of the sale of personal information or use of it for targeted advertising above under “Your Right to Opt Out of the Sale of Personal Information and Targeted Advertising.”

We will endeavor to respond to your requests within 45 days, but it may take up to 90 days. If we need more than 45 days, we will contact you to let you know that we need additional time.

**Questions.** If you have questions about your rights under the Colorado, Connecticut, Oregon, Texas, Utah or Virginia state privacy laws or about our privacy policies and practices, email us at [privacy@tracfone.com](mailto:privacy@tracfone.com).

**Nevada Privacy Rights**

Nevada law allows customers to opt out of the sale of their personally identifiable information by online service providers such as website operators. Nevada law defines "sale" as the exchange of certain personally identifiable customer information for money. Personally identifiable information includes name, address, phone number, SSN, or any identifier that can be used to contact you electronically.

TracFone may disclose information that identifies you with a partner who facilitates your interactions with third parties, including for verifying your identity and providing information to assist with a decision on a credit application you have submitted to a bank or other third party. Nevada law may consider this activity a sale of personal information.

To opt out please visit our Your Privacy Choices pages, available at:

* https://www.tracfone.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns
* https://www.straighttalk.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns
* https://www.simplemobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns
* https://www.net10wireless.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns
* https://www.myfamilymobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns
* https://www.totalbyverizon.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns
* https://www.safelinkwireless.com/en/#!/ypc
* https://www.gosmartmobile.com/ccpa/home?reqType=dns

**Additional Information for Oregon Residents**

TracFone Wireless, Inc. is registered as active with the Oregon Secretary of State.

### **Changes To This Policy**

We may make changes to this Policy, so please check back periodically. When we do, we will revise the effective date above. If we decide to use or disclose information that identifies you personally in a way that is materially different from what we stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected that information from you, we will give you a choice about the new use or disclosure by appropriate means, which may include an opportunity to opt out.

### **How to Contact Us**

Please direct any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy to:

privacy@tracfone.com

Verizon Privacy Office

1300 I Street, NW Suite 500 East

Washington, DC 20005

America’s largest prepaid, no-contract wireless service provider.

### Site Map

### Brands

* Straight Talk Wireless
    
* Tracfone
    
* SIMPLE Mobile
    
* Total by Verizon
    
* SafeLink Wireless
    
* Walmart Family Mobile
    
* NET10 Wireless
    
* Page Plus Cellular
    
* GoSmart Mobile
    
* Clearway Wireless

### Contact

* TracFone Wireless, Inc.
* 9700 N.W. 112th Avenue
* Miami, FL 33178  
    
* Lifeline Program Information
* 1-800-723-3546
* (SafeLink)
* 1-800-973-9716
* (MyFamilyMobile)
* Verizon Migration Program Information
* 1-888-899-8789
* (California)
* 1-866-667-6437
* (Non-California)

### Policies & Notices

TRACFONE®, NET10®, STRAIGHT TALK®, SIMPLE MOBILE®, Total by Verizon®, PAGE PLUS and SAFELINK WIRELESS® are registered trademarks of TracFone Wireless Inc., a Verizon company.  All other trademarks, service marks, and trade names referenced in this site are the property of their respective owners. View our [Privacy Policy](https://www.tracfonewirelessinc.com/en/Privacy+Policy/).
